Guide to the Urie Bronfenbrenner papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
Bronfenbrenner, Urie papers, [ca. 1960-2011]
- Series V. Researcher Files
  - Work and Family: Greenberger, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Caldwell: Home Inventory Results, 1975, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Symposium - Twin Studies: Rosenthal, 1963-1969 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Prenatal Intervention: Kotelchuk, 1983-1985 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Prenatal Stress, 1967-1989 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Prematurity: Rauk, 1987-1988 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Prenatal Complications: Pasamanick, 1958-1984 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Prenatal Influences: Retrospective and Prospective, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Life Expectancy: Sex Differences (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Changing American Population (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Maternal Behavior - Mammals, 1963 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Bonding - Primary, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Mother-Infant Bonding: Hales, 1975-1976 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Mother-Neonate: Movement, 1973-1993 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Beckwith et al, 1981-1984 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Robert Foster Cherry Award, 1990-1991 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - Roles and Publicity (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Janakov, Blagoja, 1995, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Declined Requests, 1999 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Faxed Material, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - HD 610 Articles, 2000 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - HDFS 685, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Graphs (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - HDFS 690, 1996 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - HDFS 488, 1988, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - HDFS 488, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - HDFS/Psych 485, 1983-7 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - HDFS 685: Life Course Seminar, 1993 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - Materials for Seminar (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - HDFS 685, 1993-4 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - Condry, John, 1979-1981 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - USSR Trip, 1961 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - Veterans Administration: Assessment, 1946-7 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - University of Michigan: University Elementary School, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - Borden General Hospital: General Program, 1946 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - Borden General Hospital: Psychology Program, 1945-1959 (Box 23, Folder 38)
  - Institute of Clinical Psychology: University of Michigan, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 39)
  - Veterans Administration: Coordinated Program of Research, 1946-7 (Box 23, Folder 40)
  - Socialization Practices and Social Structure in the Kibbutz as related to Personality Development, 1991-01 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Items Influencing GPA, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - National Longitudinal Study of Adolescent Health (Box 27, Folder 9)
- Series VI. Audiotapes and Sound Recordings
  - The American Family - Who Cares?, 1975-9 (Box 23)
  - The American Family - Who Cares? Andragogy Institute, 1977 (Box 23)
  - Bronfenbrenner Interview: Richard Hult, 1979-08 (Box 23)
  - Last Class: Human Development in Post-Industrial Society - Tape 1 of 2, 1984-05-03 (Box 23)
  - Last Class: Human Development in Post-Industrial Society - Tape 2 of 2, 1984-05-03 (Box 23)
  - The Ecological System: Overview, 1983 (Box 24)
  - Lecture 3: Prenatal Development, 1983 (Box 24)
  - Lecture 4: Drugs and Prenatal, 1983 (Box 24)
  - Beginning of Perinatal Lecture, 1983-02-08 (Box 24)
  - Perinatal Continued, 1983-02-08 (Box 24)
  - Bonding, 1983-02-22 (Box 24)
  - Tulkin, 1983-02-24 (Box 24)
  - Tulkin: Cultural Deprivation, 1983-03-01 (Box 24)
  - Messer & Lewis, Crockenburg, 1983-03-03 (Box 24)
  - Crockenburg, 1983-03-08 (Box 24)
  - Education and I.Q., 1983-03-10 (Box 24)
  - Lecture, 1983-03-15-1983-03-17 (Box 24)
  - End of March 15th, Beginning of March 17th, 1983-03-15-1983-03-17 (Box 24)
  - Criminality: Genetics and Environment, 1983-03-21 (Box 24)
  - Crowe & Scarr, 1983-03-24 (Box 24)
  - Levy & Symond, Parent-Child Relationships, 1983-04-05 (Box 24)
  - Scarr-Bronfenbrenner Exchange, 1983-04-14 (Box 24)
  - Levy, Symond, Baumrind vs. Tulkin, 1983-04-19 (Box 24)
  - Malnutrition (Box 24)
  - SRCD with Scarr (Box 24)
  - Encounters of the Third Kind (Box 24)
  - Cross-Cultural Comparisons of Childhood Development (Box 24)
  - Cornell Convocation: Part I, 1988-02-07 (Box 24)
  - Cornell Convocation: Part II, 1988-02-07 (Box 24)
  - An Interview with Urie Bronfenbrenner: Part I, 1975 (Box 24)
  - An Interview with Urie Bronfenbrenner: Part II, 1975 (Box 24)
  - An Interview with Urie Bronfenbrenner: Part III, 1975 (Box 24)
  - Bronfenbrenner TV Interview, 1976-05 (Box 24)
  - APA Master Lecture Series, 1976-10 (Box 24)
  - Actuality: America Family Feature, 1977-03-04 (Box 24)
  - Interview with Alan Bickley, 1980-09-25 (Box 24)
  - Colloquium Prof. H. Kojima, 1985-05-01 (Box 24)
  - Actuality: Human Ecology Institute, May 10,19?? (Box 24)
  - Social Change: The Challenge to Research and Policy: Part I (Box 24)
  - Social Change: The Challenge to Research and Policy: Part II (Box 24)
  - HDFS 115 Experiment (Box 24)
  - Open Education Conference: Helping Children to Become Human: Opening School and Communities to Each Other, 1972-04-22 (Box 24)
  - Michigan State University: East Lansing (Box 24)
  - Child Care and Education in Communist China (Box 24)
  - "The Impact of Peers"- sound recording (2 copies), 1967; SR 1121
- Series VII. Videotapes and Films
  - Center for Improvement of Undergraduate Education - HDFS 115 Study - 14 1/2 minutes (Box 24)
  - Families In The Balance (VHS) (Box 24)
  - Curriculum For Caring: Ruffing Montessori, Cleveland Heights (VHS) (Box 24)
  - Seasons of Life: Young Adulthood (VHS), 1987-04-11 (Box 24)
  - Seasons of Life: Late Adulthood (VHS), 1987-04-11 (Box 24)
  - Kindergarten: The First Day, The First Year (VHS) (Box 24)
  - What Soviet Children Are Saying About Nuclear Weapons (VHS), 1984 (Box 24)
  - Childhood: Among Equals - Ambrose Video Publishing, Inc., V-261 (Box 32)
  - Childhood: Great Expectations - Ambrose Video Publishing, Inc., V-262 (Box 32)
  - Childhood: The House of Tomorrow - Ambrose Video Publishing, Inc., V-263 (Box 32)
  - Childhood: Life's Lessons - Ambrose Video Publishing, Inc., V-264 (Box 32)
  - Childhood: Louder Than Words - Ambrose Video Publishing, Inc., V-265 (Box 32)
  - Childhood: Love's Labors - Ambrose Video Publishing, Inc., V-266 (Box 32)
  - Childhood Program 1, Rough Cut, 1991-01-28; V-267 (Box 32)
  - Head Start NOW! - Produced by the Children's Defense Fund, Supported by AARP, V-268 (Box 32)
  - Instructional Services Center, University of South Carolina - Dr. Urie Bronfenbrenner, 1990-04-27; V-269 (Box 32)
  - Urie Bronfenbrenner - Jones Distinguished Lecture, University of California, Berkeley, 1992-02-26; V-270 (Box 32)
  - Nature/Nurture Reconceptualized - Urie Bronfenbrenner and Stephen C., 1993-03-29; V-271 (Box 32)
  - Urie Bronfenbrenner - Campbell Hall, 1993-03-30; V-272 (Box 32)
  - Academic Leadership Series: Series Three, V-273 (Box 32)
  - Everybody's Business: America's Children; and Young Storytellers in Russia, V-274 (Box 32)
  - In the Land of Giants - Ambrose Video Publishing, Inc., V-9005 (Box 32)
  - Center for Improvement of Undergraduate Education: HD&FS 115 Study, F-1625
  - Three Worlds of Childhood, 1975; F-1626
  - Three Worlds of Childhood, 1975; F-1627
    1 reel of color camera negative and 1 reel of B negative.
  - School Starts Before Six (Film with no sound about Head Start), no date; Film F-474
    Filmed at the Cornell Nursery School by Norman Cohen.
  - HDFS 115 Lecture "The Development of Human Behavior", F-1627
  - Bronfenbrenner Lectures, DVD-718 (Box 32)
    Digitized from VHS V-270 - V-273
- Series VIII. Interviews
  - "Development and Ecological Context: History of the Psychological Science: Personal View and Experience - An Interview with Urie Bronfenbrenner" (In German), 1986 (Box 25, Folder 91)
  - Bronfenbrenner Interview (Beginning in German), 1990-07-22 (Box 25, Folder 92)
  - Interview with Bronfenbrenner by Dr. Donata Elschenbroich (In German), 1990-10-18 (Box 25, Folder 93)
  - "Gibt es Universalien in der Kindererzie hung? Ein Interview mit Urie Bronfenbrenner", 1992 (Box 25, Folder 94)
  - Borstelmann Interview with Bronfenbrenner, 1992-08-20 (Box 25, Folder 95)
  - Interview with Brofrenbrenner by Sheldon W. White for the Foundation for Child Development, 1998-12 (Box 25, Folder 96)
  - SRCD Oral History - Urie Bronfenbrenner Interviewed by Glen Elder, 1998-10-18 (Box 25, Folder 97)
  - Interview of Glen Elder by Urie Bronfenbrenner (Box 25, Folder 98)
  - Interviews with Bronfenbrenner(In German), 1986,1992 (Box 31, Folder 6)
- Series IX. Programs of Interest and/or Involvement for Bronfenbrenner
  - Cornell Parent Behavior Description - An Interim Report, 1966-10 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Pre-Kindergarten Program, 1980-1992 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Russian Academy of Eduction Publications, 1981-1996 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Cornell's Common Learning Program: A proposal for Expansion and Diversification, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - UNESCO, 1985-1989 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - The Family Support Act, 1988-1990 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (Bronfenbrenner, participant), 1989-09 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Smith Richardson Foundation, 1989-1991 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Head Start: General, 1989-2001 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Max Planck Institute Publications, 1990-1999 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - "Childhood" PBS Series including quotes from Bronfenbrenner, 1991-10 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - The Statement of the Advisory Committee on Services for Families with Infants and Toddlers (Bronfenbrenner on committee), 1994-09 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Goals 2000: Educate America Act, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - BLCC: Annual Reports and Publications, 1995-2001 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Board on the Behavioral, Cognitive and Sensory Sciences, 1996 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - 14th Annual IACAPAP, Stockholm, Sweden, List of Participants, 1998-08-02-1998-08-06 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - Baehr v. Miike Decision sent from Bibson, Dunn & Crutcher, LLP, 2000-02-18 (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - "Trends in the Well Being of America's Children and Youth,", 2001 (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - Tompkins Community Action, 2001-2002 (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - Journal of Russian and East European Psychology (Bronfenbrenner on Advisory Committee), 2002-05-2002-06 (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Event honoring Urie Bronfenbrenner, 2005 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Series X. Statistics Figures (Paper and Transparency copies)
  - Statistics on Monitoring Grades (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Statistics about the Elderly (Box 26, Folder 22)
  - Notes/Statistics on Monitoring Sexual Activity (Box 26, Folder 23)
  - Statistics on Parental Responsiveness (Box 26, Folder 24)
  - Statistics on Teenage Birth (Box 26, Folder 25)
  - Transparencies on Figures on Children and Families (Box 26, Folder 26)
  - Transparencies and Copies of Figures on Well-Being (Box 26, Folder 27)
  - "Snapshots of America's Children" Statistics Transparencies, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 28)
  - Children and Families Statistic Figures, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 29)
- Series XI. Articles in which Bronfenbrenner is Cited/Quoted
  - "17-year old Swedish Teenagers Look Back on their Time in Daycare," Bengt Andersson and Kerstin Strander (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - "Child Development and Social Policy" Edward Ziegler (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Asian article with cites Bronfenbrenner (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - "Socialization in Cross-Cultural Perspective: A Comparative Study of England, Germany, and the United States" Edward Devereaux, Jr., 1965-08 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - "Families in the East and West Socialization Process and Kinship Ties" Edward Devereux, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - "Authority and Moral Development Among German and American Children: a Cross-National Pilot Experiment" Edward Devereux, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - "Structural Equation Models and Causal Inference in Child Development Research" Sueann Ambron and David Rogosa, 1975 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - "Effects of Caregiver Behavior on Habituation Rate and Self-Efficacy in Infants" J. Marianne Riksen-Walraven, 1978 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - "Causal Model in Early Education Research" Sueann Ambron, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - "Long-Term Effects of Two Interventions with the Aged: An Ecological Analysis" David Ransen, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - "The Sociogenesis of Self Concepts" Robert and Beverly Cairns, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - "Mentors in Adolescents' Lives" Stephen Hamilton and Nancy Darling, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - "Classroom Contextual Effects on Children's Play" A.D. Pellegrini and Jane Perlmutter, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - "Okologische Psychologie Ein Handbuch in Schiusselbegriffen" Herausgegeben von Leneliskruse et al., 1990 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - "'Pygmalion's' Self-Perception: Some Thoughts on the Development of the Socio-Educational Identity", 1990-1999 (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - "Zunehumendes Risikoverhalten unter Jugendllchen" Von Prof. R.E. Muuss, 1990-1999 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - "Childhood Experience, Interpersonal Development and Reproductive Strategy: An Evolutionary Theory of Socialization" Jay Belsky, Laurence Steinberg, and Patricia Draper, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - "Experiential Canalization of Behavior Development: Theory" Gilbert Gottlieb, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - "Beyond the Reaction Range Concept: A Developmental, Contextual, and Situational Model of the Heredity-Environment Interplay" Mark Benson, 1992 (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - "Genetics, Nurture, and Social Development: An Alternative Viewpoint" Theodore Wachs, 1990-1999 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - "Expanding the Ecology of Human Development: An Evolutionary Perspective" Jay Belsky, 1995, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - "Developmental Behavior Genetics: Fusion, Correlated Constraints, and Timing" Robert Cairns et al., 1993 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Head Start and Beyond, Edward Ziegler and Sally J. Syfco (Eds.), 1993 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Seminar on the Life Course Taught by Glen Elder, Jr., Spring (Box 27, Folder 32)
    Took place in the Spring
  - "Parent-Caregiver Communication and Quality of Care in Diverse Child Care Settings" Alisa Ghazvini and Christine Readdick, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - "Response to Commentaries" Robert Plomin, 1994 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - "Authoritative Parenting and Adolescent Adjustment: An Ecological Journey" Steinberg et al., 1995 (Box 27, Folder 35)
  - "Social Ecology Over Time and Space" Robert and Beverly Cairns, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 36)
  - "Agency, Control, and Means-Ends Beliefs About School Performance in Moscow Children: How Similar Are The to Beliefs of Western Women?" Stetsenko, et al., 1995 (Box 27, Folder 37)
  - "The Life Course and Human Development" Glen Elder, Jr., 1996-04 (Box 27, Folder 38)
  - "Family Experience in Preadolescence and the Development of Male Delinquency" Caughlin and Vuchinich, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 39)
  - "Correlated Constraints in Development: Individual Profiles and Social Networks in Teen Parenthood" Hongling Xie, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - "Habits of Mind for a Learning Society: Educating for Human Development" Daniel Keating, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 41)
  - "Competence and Coping in Adolescence: Developmental Transitions and Diversity" Daniel Keating and Darla MacLean, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 42)
  - "The Evolutionary Study of Human Family Systems" Stephen Emlen, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 43)
  - "Constructing the Self: Comparing Post-Vygotskian and Discourse-Based Versions of Social Constructionism" Anna Stetsenko and Igor Arievitch, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 44)
  - "Career Development in Adolescent Girls: Impact of Control Beliefs, Gender Identity, and Societal Barriers" Anna Stetsenko, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 45)
  - "A New Genre: Contra-Bell Curve" Melvin Kohn, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 46)
  - "Ecological perspectives in Human Development: A Comparison of Gibson and Bronfenbrenner" Johnathan Tudge, Jacquelyn Gray, and Diane Hogan, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 47)
  - "The Life Course as Developmental Theory" Glen Elder, Jr., 1997 (Box 27, Folder 48)
  - "The Development of Social and Communicative Competence in Childhood: Review and Model of Personal, Familial, and Extrfamilial Processes" Hart, Olsen, Robinson, Mandleco, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 49)
  - "Theoretical Foundations of a Program of Home Visitation for Pregnant Women and Parents of Young Children" Olds et al., 1997-01 (Box 27, Folder 50)
  - "Integrating and Emotional Regulation Perspective in a Program of Prenatal and Early Childhood Home Visitation" Robinson et al., 1997-01 (Box 27, Folder 50)
  - "Parental Involvement in Adolescent Schooling: A Proximal Process with Transcontextual Validity" Karen Bogenschneider, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 51)
  - "Action Perspectives on Human Development" Jochen Brandtsadter, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 52)
  - "The Popularity of Friendship and the Neglect of Social Networks: Toward a New Balance" Robert Cairns, Hongling Xie, and Man-Chi Leung, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 53)
  - "Do Extracurricular Activities Protect Against Early School Dropout?" R. Cairns and J. Mahoney, 1997 (Box 27, Folder 54)
  - "Social Networks and Aggressive Behavior: Peer Support or Rejection?" R. Cairns, et al., 1998 (Box 27, Folder 55)
  - "Children, Cities, and Psychological Theories, Developing Relationships" (Foreword by Bronfenbrenner), 1998 (Box 27, Folder 55)
  - "The Making of Developmental Psychology" Robert Cairns, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 56)
  - "Revisiting Children of the Great Depression" Glen Elder, Jr., 1998-03 (Box 27, Folder 57)
  - "Normally Occurring Environmental and Behavioral Influences on Gene Activity: From Central Dogma to Probabilistic Epigenesis" Gilbert Gottlieb, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 58)
  - "Academic Achievement of African American Preadolescents: The Influence of Teacher Perceptions" Sherri Seyfried, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 59)
  - "The School Compositional Effect of Single Parenthood on 10th-grade Achievement" Suet-ling Pong, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 60)
  - "Examining Proximal Processes in Young Children's Home Environments: A Preliminary Report" Sarah Pierce and Elizabeth Alfonso, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 61)
  - "Can Mothers Win? The Transformation of Mother-Daughter Relationships in Late Childhood" Lothar Krappmann, Beale Schuster, and James Youniss, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 62)
  - "Grandparenting in Family Systems: An Ecological Perspective" Kung, Russell, Elder, 1998 (Box 27, Folder 63)
  - "Overt and Relational Aggression in Russian Nursery-School-Age Children: Parenting Style and Marital Linkages" Hart et at., 1998 (Box 27, Folder 64)
  - "Russian Parenting Styles and Family Processes: Linkages with Subtypes of Victimization and Aggression" Hart et al., 1998 (Box 27, Folder 65)
  - "Peer Acceptance in Early Childhood and Subtypes of Socially Withdrawn Behavior in China, Russia, and the United States" Hart et al., 1998 (Box 27, Folder 66)
  - "Same Beings, Different Stories: A Comparison of American and Chinese Narratives" Qi Wang and Michelle Leichtman, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 67)
  - The Future of Children, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 68)
  - "An Ecodevelopmental Framework for Organizing the Influences on Drug Abuse: A Develomental Model of Risk and Protection" Jose Szapocznik and J. Douglas Coatsworth, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 69)
  - "Propositions Related to the Ecology of Human Development", 1999 (Box 27, Folder 70)
  - "Challenges Posed by Place and Other Issues", 1999 (Box 27, Folder 70)
  - "The Adjustment of Children with Divorced Parents: A Risk and Resiliency Perspective" E. Mavis Hetherington and Margaret Stanley-Hagan, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 71)
  - "Predictors of Leaving Home in Young Adults Raised in Germany: A Replication of a 1991 Study" Juang, Silbereisen, Wiesner, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 72)
  - "Supportive Parenting and Adolescent Adjustment Across Time in Former East and West Germany" Linda Juang and Rainer Silberseisen, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 73)
  - "Effects of Quantity and Quality of Home Prozima Processes on Butch, Surinamese-Dutch and Turkish Dutch Preschoolers' Cognitive Development" Paul Leseman and Dymphna van den Boom, 1999 (Box 27, Folder 74)
  - "Developmental Science: Three Audacious Implications" Rober Cairns, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 75)
  - "Residential Crowding in the Context of Inner City Poverty" Gary Evans and Susan Saegert, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 76)
  - "Exploring and Defining Early Social Ecologies and Their Impact: Mothers, Fathers, Families and Cultures" Michael Lamb, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 77)
  - "Maternal Addiction, Child Maladjustment, and Socio-demographic Risks: Implications for Parenting Behaviors" Nancy Suchman and Suniya Luthar, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 78)
  - "An Ecological Analysis of Monthly 'Bursts' in Early Adolescent Substance Use" Thomas Dishion and Nani Medici Skaggs, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 79)
  - "Paradise Lost and Found: Positive Environments for Adolescent Development - Past, Present and Future" Review by Reed Larson and Suzanne Wilson of 'Children of the Land: Adversity and Success in Rural America' by Glen Elder, Jr., 2000 (Box 27, Folder 80)
  - "What Do Adolescents Need for Healthy Development? Implications for Youth Policy" Jodie Roth and Jeanne Brooks-Gunn, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 81)
  - "Child Development and Social Policy" Edward Zigler, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 82)
  - "The Self-Sufficiency Project of 36 Months: Effects on Children of a Program that Increased Parental Employment and Income" Pamela Morris and Charles Michalapoulos, June 2000 (Box 27, Folder 83)
  - "Gifted Infants: What Kinds of Support do they Need?" J. Marianne Riksen-Walraven and Jolien Zevalkink, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 84)
  - "More that Line Leader and Door Holder: Engaging Young Children in Real Work" Christine Readdick and Kathy Douglas, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 85)
  - "Interpretations of the Past and Expectations for the Future in Two Conflicted Societies: The Case of Israeli and Palestinian Youth" Shifra Sagy, Avi Kaplan, Sami Adwan, 2000 (Box 27, Folder 86)
  - "Divorce and Children's Cognitive Ability" John Guidubaldi and Julie Duckworth, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 87)
  - "Family Capital and South African Young Adults' Self-Concept" Kevin Marjoribanks and Mzobazim Mboya, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 88)
  - "Adolescent Development" Laurence Steinberg and Amanda Sheffield Morris, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 89)
  - "Predicting Teen Motherhood and Teen Fatherhood: Individual Characteristics and Peer Affiliations" Hongling Xie, Beverly Cairns, and Robert Cairns, 2001 (Box 27, Folder 90)
  - "The Life Course and Aging: Challenges, Lessons, and New Directions" Glen Elder, Jr. and Monica Kirkpatrick Johnson, 2003 (Box 27, Folder 91)
  - "Biology Environment Interaction and Evocative Biology-Environment Correlation: Contributions of Harsh Discipline and Parental Psychopathology to Problem Adolescent Behaviors" Riggins-Caspers et al., May 2003 (Box 27, Folder 92)
  - PsycINFO and ERIC citations which Refer to Bronfenbrenner but are not authored by him as of, 2002-04-30 (Box 27, Folder 93)
  - Bronfenbrenner quoted: New York Times, 1992-11-08 (Box 26, Folder 63)
  - Bronfenbrenner quoted: Human Ecology, 2000-10 (Box 26, Folder 63)
  - Bronfenbrenner quoted: Human Ecology, 1987-10-19 (Box 26, Folder 63)
  - Bronfrenner quoted: Behavior Science, 2000-10 (Box 26, Folder 63)
  - Bronfenbrenner in the News, 1996-2000 (Box 26, Folder 64)
  - Newspaper articles featuring Bronfenbrenner, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 65)
  - Notes and newspaper articles (Box 26, Folder 66)
  - Articles about Urie Bronfenbrenner of various dates (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Articles about Urie Bronfenbrenner of various dates (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Articles about Urie Bronfenbrenner, 1954-2004 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
  - Papers about Bronfenbrenner, written in German (Box 30, Folder 21)
- Series XII. Awards
  - Regents Medal of Excellence, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Awards (Box 14-15)
  - Certificate - University of Michigan Scholar, 1942-1943 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Awards, 1980-2000 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Honorary degree from the Technical University of Berlin, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 9)